what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbend.com today I am running through
the best fat burners for men the best
fat burning supplement now don't get it
twisted if you are trying to lose fat a
calorie deficit is what is required
that's the most important thing uh you
want to make sure that your
macronutrients are in check so you're
losing as much fat and retaining as much
muscle as possible nonetheless there's
some pretty interesting supplements out
there that could potentially help to
burn a few extra calories you wouldn't
have otherwise plus burn a bit more fat
than you would otherwise and perhaps
have lower appetite than you would have
otherwise so those are like the ways
that fat burners work I've got a wide
range of them here so stick around we're
going to talk about the best fat burner
for bodybuilders the best natural fat
burner the best fat burning powder as
well as answering some common questions
that we get around these supplements
because of all the supplements we cover
we probably get the most questions about
fat burners now before I go on I need to
make it clear that I am not a doctor or
a medical professional and this video
does not constitute medical advice
that's the disclaimer that's pretty
important for basically any supplement
video but especially one like this so if
you applying to make any changes to your
supplement regimen or nutrition regimen
exercise regimen anything like that make
sure you talk to a doctor who has
knowledge about you and your own
individual history medications needs and
so on I'm just going to tell you what
our number one product is here the
number one fat Banner floor man is
eliminate by huge supplements to get
this terrifying flaming Grim Reaper in
the front there's actually quite a lot
of pretty cool ingredients on this one
right so a lot of the most popular fat
burners just about every fat burner is
going to have these two ingredients
green tea extract and Kathy Max or like
red chili pepper extract right both
those are in here both those could
potentially help to increase the amount
of calories it would have been otherwise
increased fat oxidation as well
potentially reduce appetite too those
are some other ones here that are seen a
little bit less often but have some
pretty interesting research supporting
them like green coffee bean extract with
50 chlorogenic acid which actually meets
the minimum amount recommended in
studies which a lot of times products
don't when that could help to
potentially decrease the absorption of
your calories so like yeah you can eat
like a little bit more than you
otherwise potentially particularly in
the realm of carbohydrates and sugars
you've also got some interesting
extracts here I'm going to get into that
in a little bit first of all though
water fat burners and how are the
different ways that they could
potentially work on your body
[Music]
so there are three main ways that fat
burners actually work right one is
actually burning fat so we call this fat
oxidation and what I'm talking about
there is that generally the body
generally uses two forms of stored
energy for like exercise you're just
generally is for going about your day
when installed carbohydrates like
glycogen the other is stored fat uh
generally been like a mixture of the two
of them and sometimes certain activities
will burn more of one than the other and
what ingredients are designed for fat
oxidation can do potentially is to Coke
somebody to burn more fat for fuel than
it would have otherwise so good examples
of that are like egcg which is the type
of antioxidant found in green tea also
L-Carnitine as well appears to be able
to coax more fat to be burned as well so
the increased fat oxidation that's one
of them there are two other important
areas though there's thermogenesis like
increased thermogenesis thermogenesis is
heat creating so it makes the body burn
more calories than whatever otherwise by
ever so slightly increasing the internal
temperature it's not like you feel like
you're on fire or anything but
ingredients that increase demogenesis
can potentially help to you to burn more
calories than you would have if you
hadn't taken those products a lot of
time it's just like 30 calories but
there are actually studies on certain
ingredients especially some of the ones
that were found in our top pick that
could potentially get you up to one to
three hundred calories which is pretty
significant uh the last one is appetite
suppression this is probably the most
important uh part of a fat burning
equation in my opinion because you can
have thermogenesis help you to build an
extra couple hundred calories but if you
wind up eating those couple hundred
calories back then like it's not really
going to be doing that much for you
right now when I'm talking about
appetite suppression I'm talking about
ingredients like glucomannan for
Japanese conjunct tree or 5-HTP through
different mechanisms they can basically
helps reduce the sensations of hunger in
like a fairly natural way because these
are both plant extracts when you're not
as hungry you're going to be eating less
and that is I think the majority of
people the number one thing they
struggle with is just like staying on
top of the calorie goals and learning to
kind of power through hunger if it
arises right there are other ways of
combating that eating a lot of fiber and
protein and so on but sometimes you just
need a bit of extra help and appetite
suppressants uh they can be really
really helpful all right so let's start
with our number one pick this is
eliminate from huge supplements uh so
this one a few Awards here right so it's
the best overall fat burner on the
market all the stuff we looked at we
think this is the best job of really
covering like a wide variety of bases
and the doses are really impressive as
well as I kind of alluded to earlier in
the supplement industry and this is true
of like basically every kind of
supplement like everything from like
pre-workouts to multivitamins they'll
say hey look that's interesting research
on like let's say cinefrin so look we
put cinnamon in our product but then
when you look really closely it's not
close to the doses used in the studies
that suggest it could be effective right
that's not something that a Hughes
softness does they have like really
significant amounts of like all the
ingredients in here so for instance like
the one I mentioned earlier the
chlorogenic acid and green coffee bean
extracts that is like a good strong
amount I've seen plenty of fat banners
with much lower amounts but this has
like well well over like 150 milligrams
or so that's been suggested in some
research to potentially help to decrease
absorption of certain calories you also
get a lot of interesting Citrus extracts
in here which might sound a bit
interesting but like a hesperidin the
synephrine there's narengen and these
ingredients you don't see them very
often but there have been some pretty
curious studies that have found that
when putting them all together these
extracts can sort of help to amplify one
of its effects and then create and lead
to increased calorie Burns so that's
like a thermogenic aspect of it and so
there's a lot of interesting ingredients
like that that you can tell they've
really done their homework on both like
the ingredients and the dosing as well
so this is our favorite men's fat burner
overall it's also our favorite for belly
fat we always get asked with the best
fat burner for belly fat is truthfully
spot reduction isn't really such a thing
in the world of fat loss but what we
like about this is that if you're
struggling with losing fat around your
midsection products like this are really
effective at targeting all the different
ways a person can benefit all at once so
what I'm saying there is there's stuff
in here for thermogenesis stuff for fat
oxidation stuff for appetite control all
of these are going on here but there's
also stuff in here that can help you to
have more productive workouts like
there's stuff like fioramine which can
increase blood flow which can
potentially help you to get better pumps
and also have more power output in the
gym and also perhaps most importantly
there is 350 milligrams of caffeine in a
full capsule serving of this in addition
to that you've got some your him Bean as
well which is very rare like there are
like maybe two or three legal stimulants
out there and uh two of them are
caffeine and you're him being you're him
being very seldom seen um but as you're
him being in this uh this is why we also
need the best fat burner for
bodybuilders
there's a lot of stuff in here that can
help to really produce a serious calorie
burn and also to give a lot of energy to
get through a workout when you're on a
low calorie diet one thing that we hear
time and time again from the
bodybuilders that we speak to at bar Ben
is they are so low in calories and they
are doing so much cardio and doing so
much working out that at that level when
you're a competitive bodybuilder that
last month especially the last couple of
weeks before a show you are trying to
get your body to do superhuman things
basically like to be able to perform and
look great while on very low calories
and likely pretty terrible sleep so what
this does here is it's got plenty of
stimulants in it to help you get through
a workout and have a productive time in
the gym even if you are pretty low on
calories in addition to having enough
ingredients here for calorie burn that
like you're going to be burning in like
the low three figures extra calories
when you're a bodybuilder approaching
competition day one to 300 calories can
make a massive difference like you can
maybe let's say if you've been told to
consume 1500 calories a day but you just
can't have less than 1800 calories
without feeling terrible taking a
product like this could potentially help
to burn an extra one or two or three
hundred calories uh with that you're
having to actually eat that much less so
bodybuilders this is still like a
different Universe like most people when
they're trying to lose fat but when you
are a competitive bodybuilder uh the
ingredients in this product we've found
can really help to exert useful effects
when you're really about getting the
numbers very very precise next up when
it comes to supplements like this a lot
of folks worry about the cost like it
has like more ingredients sometimes
harder to find ingredients so we often
get asked what the best fat burner is
for the money and so for that one we
went with Wolverine's therm it's very
inexpensive for 35 bucks you're getting
90 servings so this one is up at 39
cents a serving uh which is very
inexpensive and you're still getting
like a lot of the more common fat
burning ingredients here that have like
a pretty good reputation in the industry
so we're talking about things like green
tea leaf extract here the Garcinia
Cambogia as well which could potentially
help to increase fat loss there's been a
bell Leaf too which might help with
insulin sensitivity and the more insulin
sensitive you are the more likely the
carbohydrates are not going to be stored
as fat and so on this is a really wide
range of ingredients but it keeps the
price like kind of shockingly low to be
fair like the doses are a bit lower than
you're going to find now the products
are but they still manage to reach a
pretty effective doses not quite as high
as some other products but for the price
this is very good and if you're not sold
you can always take like a few of these
a day and you're still going to wind up
paying like under a dollar or around a
dollar per day so pretty good value from
Wolverine stem which you also need the
best thermogenic fat burner as well the
reason for that is that there's a wide
range of ingredients here that could be
linked to increased fat loss now again
your calories the most important thing
but there's still some research that has
found that like the cayenne pepper in
here can help with thermogenesis but
also appetite management there's also
the coleus for scoli that might increase
lipolysis and reduce appetite grapefruit
might help insulin sensitivity banaba
might decrease production of fat cells
the caffeine in here might provide
additional stimulation as well and extra
thermogenesis it's also worth noting
here the uh the caffeine here comes from
guarana as opposed to caffeine which
might be extra effective in that gut
over like more typical sources of
caffeine so there's a pretty wide
variety of effects here again and a wide
variety of ingredients so the fact that
they managed to keep the cost so far
under a dollar per serving like 35 cents
per serving while also being able to
kind of uh approach the fat loss puzzle
from so many different angles I found
that pretty impressive so this Wolverine
is definitely up there with one of our
favorite fat burners before I go on I
want to just make it clear that uh
there's a written version of this
article so if this is all kind of like a
lot of information or if you find me
kind of annoying you can read the
written version of this article if you
just go to Google you write in barban
best fat burners for men the whole thing
will come right up and then you can go
through it at your own pace and check
out some of the research we've been
talking about get a close look at the
ingredients and make the right decisions
for you next up we've talked a lot about
capsules and pills today but if you're
looking for the best fat burning powder
for men this is the old version of the
product
this is clean Ben from caged so this is
a powder really easy to just mix into
your regular shake your morning drink
anything like that so what's interesting
like this product is that it does have a
fair amount of caffeine in it right so
it's not a crazy amount it's like a
little bit less than you're gonna get in
just your average like 12 ounce cold
brew from a coffee shop but you're
getting still 166 milligrams of caffeine
but it's also coming from Amity which is
like I used to gayusa is like an unusual
kind of plant they used to have on the
Amazon before they would go and Lead
hunting parties and they've been some
interesting studies finding that this
particular form of caffeine uh is a
little bit better at helping someone to
maintain focus and reduce the
jitteriness I can typically accompany
like a large hit of caffeine so a lot of
folks like this just for it's a way to
increase your thermogenesis by way of
taking in caffeine but it tends to make
them a little bit less like jittery it's
also a fair amount of Thai rice in here
which could also help with that having
more focus and less jitteriness along
with it while you're getting extra
thermogenesis there's also some other
curious ingredients like Colora burn
which is a patented name for grains of
paradise extract and there have been
studies on grains of paradise which have
found that when you get the extract of
the metabolites out of them which is
what color burn is it's like a patent
way of doing that they found that it
could help to activate Brown fatty
tissue and also to uh increase total
daily caloric expenditure so caged clean
burn has a variety of ingredients here
its main emphasis is on thermogenesis
but they've also got some interesting
ingredients that could help with fat
oxidation and lean muscle retention like
kind of team should make it a pretty
good all-round fat firmness so yeah
we're a big fan of this one and uh
there's no complaining about the orange
mango flavor because it is delicious
next up we have been talking a lot about
fat burners with stimulants in them
there are good reasons to have
stimulants in a fat burner it doesn't
crystallogenesis it tends to help to
reduce appetite as well uh might have
some effects on fat oxidation but they
also are stimulants which means if you
are sensitive to stimulants or caffeine
or if you're not some of these are like
300 350 milligrams of caffeine even if
you're not sensitive to it that can
still be a lot for a lot of folks plus a
lot of folks like to take their fat
burner as before meals uh so if it's
before dinner caffeine might be an issue
so
there are some pretty fat burners out
there and the one we're talking about
for our favorite stem free fat burner is
the one from transparent Labs
transparent Labs is a pretty cool
company they really give you the exact
dosages of every single thing in the
products and they have like studies next
to them on their website to tell you why
they put it in there so in general we're
a big fan of this company so a lot of
the ingredients here are meant to Aid
with fat metabolism and fat oxidation
like in general to make the body use
more fat for energy and get more fat
used up than it would have otherwise so
fuco stanthem is an interesting
ingredient for that one there's also a
subtle El carnitine which I've mentioned
in other products here it's also coleus
for scoli and cayenne pepper as well for
good measure the other ingredients here
they're based a little bit more around
appetite suppression which as I
mentioned it is a really really key for
actually losing fat and eating less
right so you've got two ones here you've
got five HTP and the adaptogenic
rhodiola rosea what's cool about this is
5 ACP as mentioned I it has some links
with serotonin which is associated with
like satiety and satisfaction so there's
a vast rare medications that interact
with serotonin for about history of
different reasons like from mental
health reasons to appetite reasons sleep
and so on it's just good to have like a
good amount of serotonin in the body
five ACP helps do that they can help
with mood and it can help with sleep and
it can help with appetite all these
things I think that people tend to
struggle with sometimes anyway when
they're on really low calorie diets
there's also rhodiola rosea in there
which is an adaptogen that can
potentially help with sleep but also
there are plenty of people who take
cordial rosea in the morning instead of
their coffee because while it isn't a
stimulant it can potentially help with
uh with focus and have like a more of a
more even amount of energy throughout
the day in addition to helping manage
stress like stress of workouts a
stressful day at the office and so on
Rodeo Rose is a really really cool
ingredient and they put it in here I
believe because when on low calorie
diets people can struggle with energy
which is another reason why a lot of
folks like to have caffeine in their fat
burners but if you don't radiologist is
actually a really really cool ingredient
that can help with energy without being
a stimulant or interfering with your
sleep so we're a big fan of the fat
burner without stimulus from transparent
Labs is our favorite free fat button
back to back transparent Labs is also
coming up for our favorite pre-workout
fat burner there are plenty of fat
burners out there that will throw in
like a proprietary blend for their fat
burning pre-workouts not telling you
what the dosages are as I already
mentioned we really like transparent
labs for being very transparent in that
regard transparent Labs lean as the name
suggests is a pre-workout that is meant
to help you to burn more fat right so
it's predominantly a pre-workout with a
bit of fat burning ingredients so the
Pre-Workout ingredients they have a lot
of interesting research behind them I
encourage you to check out our videos on
pre-workouts as well because you've got
ingredients like beta alanine for
endurance citrulline for blood flow and
so on but until that you have a healthy
dose of Othello El carnitine HCI here as
well and as I mentioned kind of seeing
there is some evidence that could
potentially help to mobilize more fatty
acids basically get you to burn a bit
more fat than you would have otherwise
and help to retain muscle as well
there's actually plenty of guys who is
like men in particular they tend to
produce less of it as they age and so
it's one of the supplements that you
often find guys taking uh when they're
concerned about the performance in the
gym and their overall health as they get
old you'll often find them taking
L-Carnitine especially El carnitine El
tatrade that's kind of a subject for
another video but the carnitine is in
here to help you burn more fat plus you
get a nice 220 milligrams of caffeine
which isn't too much but it is enough to
have an increase of thermogenesis as
well so yeah lean from transparent Labs
that's our favorite pre-workout for fat
loss next up we have the best
all-natural fat burner that one's going
to Legion Legions Phoenix it's a very
good name and also Legion in general
very good company they're kind of
similar to transparent labs in that if
you go to the website they're really
good at providing like this scientific
citations and references for the claims
they make and as to why they're using
all these ingredients and Legion also
has a big commitment to not using any
artificial ingredients in any of their
products so whether you're getting their
pre-workouts or their protein powders or
the fat burners there are no artificial
flavors sweeteners or fillers anything
like that so Legions Phoenix uh it does
come with a lot of the ingredients that
we've mentioned so far so you're getting
a nice 200 milligrams of caffeine here
to help with thermogenesis you've also
got a coleus forskoli to help with
perhaps some extra fat oxidation there
you've also got some grains in Paradise
here again which might help to activate
Brown fatty tissue and help to increase
total energy expenditure so there's a
lot of stuff in here for increased
thermogenesis and there are also some
other interesting ones like for instance
there's a black ginger extract right and
that could help to uh there's some
interesting research on that and obesity
in that it might help you stop they call
it like lipogenesis basically means it
might help to reduce the amount of new
fat cells you're creating and helping to
preserve muscle as you're losing fat as
well and then finally there's five hcp
in here as well which again links to
serotonin are great for appetite and
good for sleep and satiety as well so
Legions if any site burner it is all
natural anything you get from that
company if you want to check them out uh
they will have no artificial flavors or
anything like that if that's the angle
you want to go with for now though Luigi
Phoenix is our favorite fat burner that
is all natural the last one you want to
mention here is instant knockout as the
best premium fat burner if you've got
money to burn and fat to burn instant
knockout it really is a very uh sort of
a high level entry into this area what
we like about at it it actually doesn't
have a whole ton of ingredients at
relatively low doses which you sometimes
see they actually just like go really
hard on a handful of ingredients it's
about a half dozen active ingredients
here I want to mention the nutrition
here is actually kind of cool as well
they're thrown in more than 200 of your
daily recommended vitamin D which could
have pretty strong links to testosterone
production bone strength that kind of
stuff it's going to come in handy if
you're trying to improve your physique
and which most people are low in as well
like very few people get enough vitamin
D throughout the day there's B6 which
can help with energy production when
you're working out and the actual
ingredients they dose in here 300
milligrams of caffeine which is a pretty
significant amount yes they also add in
some theanine though and a lot of people
like to pair caffeine and theanine
because that could potentially help to
reduce the jitteriness associated with
caffeine and I improve focus like it's
very common Stephanie Coleman does that
a lot of athletes like to mix up
thinning and caffeine so plenty of
cayenne pepper to help with fat
oxidation and appetite control and this
green tea extract two so green tea
extract Cayenne Pepper caffeine these
are all really common ingredients
happens that just dorsed very well here
and then the most important thing here
which we haven't actually seen yet on
this list is the glucone Manon
glucomannan is a really impressive
appetite suppressant I encourage you to
check out some studies on it it's
basically it comes from the root of a
Japanese konjac tree and when you
consume it it swells a little bit in the
stomach to making you feel a bit more
full when you would have otherwise it's
really it's all natural it might sound a
bit like weird but it's still a natural
way to suppress appetite and a lot of
people find that really handy for fat
loss so you've got only the most
research-backed ingredients here for fat
burners there are some brands that
experiment with some interesting ones
interesting effects but this one has
gone in on the ones with the most
research supporting it so it's glucoman
and green tea extract caffeine and
cayenne powder and a nice dose of black
pepper here as well to help with
absorption to make sure you're getting
everything that you're buying so that
does it for our list of the best fat
burning supplements for men I hope you
learned something as far as when to take
it that's just like another question we
always get asked it depends on the
dosage because there's a lot of these
products where you just need to take the
dosage like frosting in the morning
there are others where you're encouraged
to take them before each meal if it's
one way you're taking it for before each
meal so let's say it's one of those fat
burners with a three pill serving size
and you're told to take them before each
meal the idea is about 20 to 30 minutes
beforehand the reason you'd wait that
long is because you're taking on an
empty stomach because it's before a meal
and it's going to take about 20 or 30
minutes before some of the effects take
place now if it's for fat oxidation or
thermogenesis it's not such a big deal
but if you talk about appetite
suppression which many of these
ingredients also do like for instance
Chili Pepper well it has links with fat
oxidation of thermogenesis it also has
some appetite suppression effects anyway
point is 20 or 30 minutes for a meal
that way you are likely to eat a bit
less during the meal if that is your
goal otherwise you can usually just take
them first in the morning the only thing
daily note of caution is that stimulants
can cause issues for some folks when it
comes to sleep so you may not want to
take them before your dinner meal in
which case you might want to be just a
bit more mindful of the amount of
calories you're consuming the last thing
to note is that some people will
experience suggested distress with fat
burners it's going to depend on gradient
and again you can find literally
anything and someone is going to get the
gist of distress from it nonetheless
when reading reviews of products now and
then you'll find someone saying like I
had a lot of trouble digesting this so
if you find a fat burner and it has like
a serving size of six pills even if that
is the effective dose it's wise to start
off with one or two uh for the first
like day or two like just one for the
whole day see how your stomach takes it
and then if you're good to go you're
good to go that's our video if you want
to see the whole written version of this
uh video you can Google it just go to
Bar band best fat banners for men on
Google it'll pop right up there and you
can go through it all at your own pace
and I hope you enjoyed the video stick
around for the next one and I'll see you
later
thank you